## Giacomo Debidda

<u>giacomodebidda.com</u> giacomo@giacomodebidda.com <u>GitHub</u> / <u>LinkedIn</u> / <u>Stack Overflow</u>



Freelance full stack developer specialized in Node.js and Google Cloud Platform. Linux user for a long time (my distro of choice is NixOS), I have been writing software professionally for almost ten years, and blogging about it since 2016. Some of the things I did are: data analysis / visualizations in <a href="Python">Python</a> and <a href="JavaScript">JavaScript</a>, web applications in TypeScript, <a href="Ibraries in Zig">Ibraries in Zig</a>, web performance audits for <a href="eCommerce">eCommerce</a> and <a href="news">news</a> websites.

## **Experience**

Freelance full stack developer @ self-employed (2020-present): Developed applications in Node.js. Open sourced a few <u>libraries</u> for frontend (11ty), backend (Hapi.js), databases (SQLite, Firestore). Experimented with <u>Clojure</u> and <u>Zig</u>.

**Software developer** @ **Develer SrI** (2018-2020): Developed frontend architecture, UI components and API endpoints for a 3D configurator software (React, Redux, Three.js, Flask).

Software developer @ Moticon GmbH (2015-2017): Developed frontend components (D3.js) and backend logic (Python) for the company flagship product.

## **Education**

Certifications: <u>Professional Data Engineer</u>, <u>Google Cybersecurity Certificate</u>, Associate Cloud Engineer.

Academia: Master in Clinical Engineering (Università di Firenze), MSc and BSc in Biomedical Engineering (Università di Pisa).

Relevant Coursework: Data Analysis and Statistical Inference, Google Cloud Database Engineer Specialization, Site Reliability Engineering: Measuring and Managing Reliability.

## **Skills**

Frontend: <a href="https://example.com/like/">https://example.com/like/</a> Progressive Web Apps, D3.js, WebGL, SVG. Backend: Next.js, <a href="https://example.com/hapi.js">Hapi.js</a>, Fastify, Platformatic, Cloudflare Workers.

Data: SQLite, Firestore, PostgreSQL, BigQuery, dbt, Apache Beam, Dagster.

Cloud: GCP, AWS, Fly.io, Cloudflare. Infra: Pulumi, Ansible, systemd.

Other: WebAssembly, Cloudinary, Stripe API, HubSpot API.